

D. JAMES RAVI

HOTEL GENERAL MANAGER

PROFILE

Multi-dimensional hotel management/pre-opening experience from individual hotel operations management to CEO of Hotel management, combined with vast international Hotel vision, can provide constructive advice for the development of hotel projects in Malaysia, Vietnam, Saipan, US & China, as well able to provide accurate orientation and planning concept for various types of hotel projects to s h a r e h o l d e r s / o w n e r s .

CONTACT

Telephone:

China :0086-13888656211 Malaysia :+601-11285-3698

Address Malaysia: B22-02, Setapak Central Condo, Jalan Danau Kota 53300 Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Address China: Phoenix Island Resort Sanya Bay 57200 Sanya, Hainan, China

Email address: james.ravi@hotmail.com james1807@gmail.com

Date of Birth: July 18, 1969 Gender: Male

Nationality: Malaysian (Christian)

Passport No: A51369601 Marital Status: Married

WEBSITE:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamesravi/

EDUCATION & AWARDS

Certified Hotel General Manager (CHGM)

SEGI COLLEGE MALAYSIA

Diploma of Hotel Management - August 2008 till June 2010

LA SALLE SCHOOL MALAYSIA

SPM - Grad 2

That's Shanghai Magazine Award The Best Night Club 2007

The Golden Dragon Award by IHIF (The 4th International Hotel Investment Forum)

G Charlton Hotels & Resorts - The Best International Hotel Management Company 2012

The International Platinum Award by CHINA HOTELS Organization Top Ten Best CEO – 2013

General Manager of the year 2020 Hainan

WORK EXPERIENCE

HOTEL GENERAL MANAGER

Jan 2018 till Present Phoenix Island Hotels & Resorts Sanya, Hainan (China)

5-star Resorts Hotels & Residences
No. of Rooms: 537
No. of F & B Outlets: 5

Banqueting & Outdoor: 1000 seating capacity Website: www.phoenix-hotels.com.cn

Responsibilities:

Accountable for leading the team to achieve the hotel's strategic goals, focusing on financial performance, service culture and employee engagement.

As well responsible for directing and leading the daily operations and providing effective leadership to the associates in achieving the hotel's strategic goals.

To maximize the financial performance of the hotel by providing the highest possible quality of guest service and product, by fostering a positive work environment for all employees, and by developing and implementing an aggressive sale and marketing plan.

Develop, implement, monitor, and participate in a comprehensive sales and marketing plan that results in optimum, rate and occupancy for the hotel. Meet or exceed established budgetary guidelines for the hotel of RMB125 million a year and GOP of 25%

Regular ongoing monitoring of staff to ensure the adherence to preestablished policies and procedures; delegation of duties; daily property inspections; active participation in community affairs; and willingness and ability to engage in effective communication with corporate staff and property owners.

Weekly forecasting and planning of operating staffing ad cost expenditures to correspond to forecasted sales and costs. Develop action plans to maximize occupancy and to maximize average rate.

CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER

Jan 2013 till Jun 2016 Lavenna Hotels & Resorts, Co. Ltd /Baoneng Holdings (China) Co., Ltd

Website: www.lavennahotels.com

Managing 32 Hotels & Resorts project development in China, which 20 under construction and 7 Chinese Restaurant Chain, meanwhile act as owner representative for Hilton & Marriott brand. Total room inventory of 4500-5000

Opened 4 hotels within 2 years plus and archived total management fee revenue of RMB48 million for total 20 hotels TS. based in Shenyang, Urumqi (3 hotels), Wuxi (2 hotels), Hefei (2 hotels), Huizhou, Nanning, Shenzhen (5 hotels), Guangzhou (2 hotels), Wuhu, Ganzhou and Beihai

- 4 Chinese restaurant 2 years revenue of RMB132 million and GOP RMB30 million
- 4 Hotels Operations 3-4 months revenue of RMB22 million

Responsibilities:

Reporting to the Company Owner/Chairman and BOD, is responsible for the company's Hotels business processes and operations, for creating necessary frameworks for existing and developing Hotels and markets, and monitoring brand and business performances closely.

Work in partnership with the EVGM and Executive Team to create the strategic five -year plan and implement new processes and approaches to achieve it.

Setting up 3 hotel brands & VI and brand development: 5 Star Lavenna, 4 Star Ravinne & Jaez Express, Spa Brand, Yacht Clubs within 3 years of Management.

Build brand partnership with local banks and airlines, travel agent/ OTA's. Create road shows around major China destinations, participate on Hotel Fairs/Exhibitions, ITB Shanghai/ Beijing/Hong Kong.

Anticipate in Hotel Owners and Independent hotel conference in Beijing and introduce Lavenna Hotels & Resorts.

Brand marketing, interactive marketing, web operations, CRM, customer loyalty and public relations.

Implementing all SOP's & P&P's of overall Hotel Management company and individual hotels and Chinese Restaurant Chain.

Develop short term action plans and long-range planning for new programs and strategies that impact the hotels based on the existing corporate directed goals and any new goals that are created. Working closely with Architects, designers, project team and construction team members on individual hotel design and concept.

Provide corporate vision and strategy into financial goals, business plans and budgets and performance targets. Direct (with the support of Executive Team) short-term and long-term planning and execution of strategic hotels business goals including acquisition and new market growth activities.

Used all kind of different approach dealing with the clientele which suits the local requirement, results driven as well responsible for aligning business goals with marketing strategies and providing an expertise that accelerates business performance and generates results. While meeting & maintaining the Standards and brand Quality.

Works collaboratively with direct reports to establish, monitor, and ensure delivery on strategic goals that align with established objectives of the individual Hotels, Chinese Restaurant Chain and Hotel Management Company.

Supports the overall process of management and corporate decision-making to ensure the organization maximizes its short-, medium- and long-term profitability and returns.

Fosters effective communications, accountability, and ownership; supports an organizational culture that promotes initiative, appropriate risk-taking, learning, creativity, cooperation, equity, and mutual respect.

Assist in developing/reviewing quarterly SMART plans. Implement and encourage hotels participation in corporate national sales and marketing programs. Communicate competitive market conditions to team executives and management.

Evaluates the effectiveness of management practices, processes, and activities; recommends or otherwise ensures appropriate measures are taken to maximize the performance of all operations.

Travel at least 50% of the time - Individual property visits to each hotel at least once each quarter. Maintain accurate records of these visits with particular attention to follow-up etc.

Lead and inspire highly experienced executives, be result-driven and a team player with strategic vision, including maintaining a high level of staff morale and allegiance to the company, and ensuring a safe and harmonious workplace for all personnel.

PRESIDENT/ CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER

Jun 2009 till Dec 2012

Aerospace Company Ltd/GCharlton Hotels & Resorts, Malaysia Co.Ltd

Managing 6 Hotels & Resorts in China and 5 hotels in Bangladesh (2 in Zhengzhou, Kunming, Linzhi, Sanya, Shenzhen & over 7 potential projects around China and Asia) with over 1700 rooms under development.

Achieved within 2 years plus total management fee revenue of RMB8 million for total 5 hotels TS.

Website: www.gcharlton.com

Responsibilities:

Establish the entire management and organization of G Charlton Hotel Management Company. Carries variety of responsibilities and tasks and do everything I could to ensure that my company is successful including brand awareness in China, Operations, marketing, strategy, financing, creation of company culture, human resources, hiring, firing, compliance with safety regulations, sales, PR, etc.—And manage to secure 5 projects after establishing the hotel brand within 2 years.

Signed MOU for Brand Development Partnership/Franchise agreement in Asia Region with Continent Hotels& Resorts. www.continenthotels.com to promote our brand worldwide.

Develop strategic plans to advance the company's mission and objectives and to promote revenue, profitability, and growth of the brand. Oversee company operations to insure development efficiency, quality, service standards, and cost-effective management of resources.

Has strong connection between the employees and board of directors. Responsible for communicating with the board and informing changes relate to the company's future or present goals. Create policies and carry out any specific actions that are recommended by the board.

Maintains a strong and positive working relationship with the Board of Directors as well as with individual Board members, to include that all Board members are kept fully appraised of the Board's and the hotel development activities.

Worked to develop the hotel management organization's objectives and policies. Meet with the company's executives and determine if the business is being operated in accordance with these objectives.

Setting up new office environment, licensing, business license & hiring/developing a team to support. -Finance, HR, Marketing, Reservation, Operation Management, Membership, Interactive marketing, Development, Procurement and General Management

Make's recommendations regarding the organization's yearly budget and make sure resources are used as efficiently as possible within those guidelines. Routinely meet with the organization's board of directors to keep them informed of the company's progress.

Is responsible for planning strategic actions as well as executing these plans to obtain additional resources as well as source for revenues that would greatly benefit the company.

Approves guidelines and procedures that will produce efficient staff members. Set certain standards to enhance the image of the company and to keep each individual employee in line with the company's goals.

Responsible for supervising the design of marketing campaign and services, as well as marketing and promotion. They may also serve as the organization's public face and convey the company's mission to stockholders and the public.

Coach and develop General Manager(s), in assigned region, in diagnosing, addressing, and resolving hotel problems; and in analyzing local market activities to determine what competitive actions should be taken.

Provide ongoing information and status reports to Management on monthly evaluations of financial and operational performance against plan. Assist team with new property marketing and financial analysis, due diligence, and hotel positioning against the competitive set.

Serve as the primary contact for hotels within the region for operations, sales and marketing, hotel initiatives and issue resolution.

Provide direction to General Managers in developing the annual business plans and strategies for each hotel and guide the development of the capital expenditure plan for area of responsibility. Identify and implement benchmark and best competitive practices for assigned region.

DEPUTY GENERAL DIRECTOR – Group (Based in the head office of the company)

Aug 2008 Till May 2009 Hien Duc Hotels & Resorts, Hanoi Vietnam 6 Hotel & Resort, Service Apartments, Office Tower Projects in Vietnam

Responsibilities:

Website: www.hienduc.com.vn

Supervise overall Management/Operations/Pre-Opening for an assigned group of hotels. Responsible for directing all General Manager's and employee's functions of these hotel properties in accordance with the policies and practices of the company. Responsibilities include the development and implementation of regional strategies for meeting goals in the areas of revenue generation, market share performance, Guest satisfaction scores, associate opinion scores, and net operating income.

Report directly to the COO of the company, Oversee rapidly expanding area of 6 Hotels, Service Apartments opening in Vietnam.

Evaluate and implement SOP's and create centralized best practices within facilities to ensure performances for each hotel are standardized.

Develop key focus areas on sales and implement company strategies at assigned hotels, oversee sales production with local corporate and group account relationship.

Drive revenue by developing key relationship with commercial and private property owners.

Participate in city and community events to expand growth in the region.

Set up corporate office and brand standards for each individual hotel. Build, train and motivate a stable team. Work closely with project team and designers for the hotel projects due to open in 2010.

Make decisions and develop plans to manage hotels in Vietnam for the owners.

HOTEL GENERAL MANAGER

Jul 2007 Till Jul 2008 Ramada Plaza Zhengzhou, Henan, China 5-star Business Hotels No. of Rooms: 302 No. of F & B Outlets: 4

Banqueting: 500 seating capacity

Website: www.ramadaplaza-zhengzhou.com

Responsibilities:

Responsible for the overall success of the pre-opening hotel, meeting or exceeding planned objectives for revenue and profit, and ensuring guest satisfaction and product quality standards are met. Manages all areas of the hotel in accordance with brand standards to achieve a friendly atmosphere of superior guest service and product quality. Provides exemplary performance for staff to follow.

Worked closely with the Project Director from a construction and operations viewpoint, and to propose changes which would result in a more efficient operation.

Supervised the operation of the hotel as efficiently as possible through qualified, well-trained staff to produce highest volume of sales.

Ensured corporate policies and procedures were followed.

Maintained building and inventories in best conditions.

Promote empowerment by recognizing team members that make decisions.

Remained competitive in all areas, prepared, and achieved budgetary goals.

Supervised and participated in the operations of the hotel to achieve the desired sales and profit goals.

Maintained the highest ethical standards of operation, quality services and facilities for the hotel and Ramada.

Developed well-trained staff with high morale and loyalty. Implements marketing and sales plans based on demand segments and to maximize **REVPAR** and Market Share.

Ensures that marketing and sales plans are appropriate for each sales period, including special plans to maximize room revenue during forecasted low occupancy.

CLUB & RESTAURANT GENERAL MANAGER

Jun 2006 Till Jun 2007 Attica Shanghai Club, Shanghai, China Club Operations with Mediterranean Rest 4000 person's capacities Awarded the best Night Club for year 2007.

Website: www.attica-shanghai.com

Managed all areas of operations including human resources, food services preparation, inventory control and management, club/restaurant sales, day-to-day financial management and administration.

EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT MANAGER

Sep 2003 Till Jun 2006 Sofitel Zhengzhou, Henan, China 5-star Business Hotels No. of Rooms: 241 No. of F & B Outlets: 4 Banqueting: 1000 seating capacity

Website: www.sofitel.com

Responsible for the overall success of the hotel, meeting or exceeding planned objectives for revenue and profit, and ensuring guest satisfaction and product quality standards are met. Assists the General manager to manage all areas of the hotel in accordance with brand standards to achieve a friendly atmosphere of superior guest service and product quality.

DIRECTOR OF FOOD & BEVERAGE

Feb 2000 Till Aug 2003 Novotel Atlantis Shanghai, China 4-star Business Hotel No. of Rooms: 303 No. of F & B Outlets: 12 Banqueting: 500 seating capacity

Website: www.novotel-shanghai-atlantis.com

Ensure that the food and beverage outlets operate profitably and efficiently and to maintain the consistency of high food and service standards in the food and beverage department. Trains and supervises subordinates and applies relevant service principles to ensure that the needs of guests are consistently exceeded.

ASSISTANT FOOD & BEVERAGE MANAGER

Jan 1998 Till Jan 2000 Tinian Dynasty Hotel & Casino, Saipan U.S.A. (Former Renaissance Hotel) 5-star Hotel and Casino No. of Rooms: 412

No. of F & B Outlets: 7

Banqueting: 600 seating capacity Website: www.tiniandynasty.com/hotel

Supervised and coordinated the pre-opening activities of the Casino Restaurant, Gaming Service, Disco and Karaoke, Chinese Restaurant and Banqueting. Provided standards and procedures training to staff from 14 different countries.

Assisted the DFB in overseeing and directing staff on daily operations of the Casino restaurants & bars and ensured service standards and guest satisfaction were maintained.

Maintained standards of food and beverage quality and guest service quality as established by system operations and regional management.

BANQUET MANAGER - In-Charge of Sales and Operations

May 1995 Till Dec 1997 Hotel Equatorial Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam 4-star Business Hotel No. of Rooms: 334 No. of F & B Outlets: 5

Banqueting: 1000 seating capacity

Website: www.hochiminhcity.equatorial.com

Managed the pre-opening banquet team training and team building for over 40 local Vietnamese staff.

Set up the Catering Sales Department. Worked closely with the DOSM on the advertising program direct mailing to accomplish increase of business.

Established client bases of organizations, associations, and corporate business. Handled catering phone inquiries and corporate catering walkin. Negotiated on food and beverage profits, function space, room rates, and hotel services.

BANQUET & CATERING SALES MANAGER

Aug 1994 Till May 1995 Dynasty Hotel, Kuala Lumpur 5-star Business Class Hotel No. of Rooms: 788

No. of F & B Outlets: 7

Banqueting: 1000 seating capacity

BANQUET MANAGER

Jun 1993 Till Jul 1994
Penang ParkRoyal Beach Resort, Malaysia
4-star Beach Resort
No. of Rooms: 333
No. of F & B Outlets: 7

Banqueting: 500 in-door and 1,200 out-door

ASSISTANT BANQUET MANAGER

Dec 1991 Till Jun 1993 Sheraton Langkawi Beach Resort, Malaysia 5-star Luxury Beach Resort No. of Rooms: 264 No. of F & B Outlets: 6 Banqueting: 600 seating capacity

SKILLS

Setting Priorities: Building short term & long term goal and plans Making decisions with incomplete data Working through others
Controlled Emotion
Building the best team
Setting the right culture
The Ability to Be Innovative
An Optimistic Nature
The Ability to Take Action
Coordination and Communication with Team Members
Inclusion in Decision Making
The Ability to Trust Others